<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Korean Fiction</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Korean Fiction</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Almond</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/almond/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/almond/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Almond&lt;/em&gt; is a coming-of-age novel that explores themes of difference, resilience, and empathy. The story follows Yunjae, a boy born with a condition called Alexithymia, which makes it hard for him to feel emotions like fear, anger, or joy. Raised lovingly by his mother and grandmother, Yunjae grows up with a system of reminders and lessons to help him navigate a world that struggles to understand him.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yunjae’s life takes a tragic turn on his sixteenth birthday when a random act of violence leaves him alone and vulnerable. Struggling to cope, his world is further shaken by Gon, a troubled teenager who initially bullies him but later becomes an unlikely friend. Through their surprising bond and the influence of others, Yunjae embarks on a journey of emotional growth, questioning what it means to be human, to feel, and to connect.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>If I Had Your Face</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cha/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cha/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If I Had Your Face&lt;/em&gt; plunges readers into the mesmerising and cutthroat world of contemporary Seoul. Through the lives of four women living in the same apartment building, Frances Cha weaves a tale of ambition, societal pressure, and tenuous friendships.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kyuri, an exquisitely beautiful woman, works at an exclusive room salon entertaining businessmen, but her status is threatened by a reckless mistake. Miho, her roommate, is a talented artist who returns to Korea after studying in New York, finding herself in a precarious relationship with a wealthy heir. Ara, a mute hairstylist, obsesses over a K-Pop star while supporting her best friend’s dream of extreme plastic surgery. Meanwhile, Wonna, a newlywed, grapples with the harsh realities of raising a child in a brutal economy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pachinko</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/lee/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/lee/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pachinko&lt;/em&gt; is a sweeping generational saga that spans the early 20th century to the 1980s, following the lives of a Korean immigrant family living in Japan. The story begins with Sunja, a poor but determined young woman, whose unexpected pregnancy leads her to reject her lover and accept a marriage proposal from a kind but sickly minister. Her decision to leave Korea for Japan sets off a chain of events that reverberates through her descendants.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Vegetarian</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/vegetarian/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/vegetarian/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Vegetarian&lt;/em&gt; is an unsettling and poetic novel that delves into the depths of nonconformity, bodily autonomy, and societal repression. When Yeong-hye, an ordinary South Korean woman, decides to stop eating meat after a disturbing dream, her life spirals into chaos. Her decision disrupts her family and community, exposing deep-seated violence, patriarchal expectations, and misunderstandings about agency.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Told through three distinct perspectives—her abusive husband, her obsessive brother-in-law, and her conflicted sister—the story paints a fragmented picture of Yeong-hye’s rebellion and eventual descent. Blurring the lines between mental illness and resistance, Kang uses dark, lyrical prose to critique societal norms and gender roles. &lt;em&gt;The Vegetarian&lt;/em&gt; is a bold, provocative exploration of identity and the human spirit, hailed for its emotional intensity and allegorical depth.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The White Book</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/white/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/white/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The White Book&lt;/em&gt; is a reflective and poetic work about loss, grief, and memory, centered around the color white. Inspired by the death of her older sister, the book explores white objects like snow, rice, and swaddling bands, tying them to themes of purity and life’s fragility. Written in short, meditative chapters, it blurs the lines between memoir, poetry, and fiction. Critics praise its lyrical language and emotional depth, offering readers a quiet, thought-provoking experience about the connections between life, death, and remembrance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
