<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Korean Fiction</title>
    <link>https://bestkoreanfiction.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Korean Fiction</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://bestkoreanfiction.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Almond</title>
      <link>https://bestkoreanfiction.github.io/almond/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bestkoreanfiction.github.io/almond/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Almond&lt;/em&gt; is a coming-of-age novel that explores themes of difference, resilience, and empathy. The story follows Yunjae, a boy born with a condition called Alexithymia, which makes it hard for him to feel emotions like fear, anger, or joy. Raised lovingly by his mother and grandmother, Yunjae grows up with a system of reminders and lessons to help him navigate a world that struggles to understand him.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yunjae’s life takes a tragic turn on his sixteenth birthday when a random act of violence leaves him alone and vulnerable. Struggling to cope, his world is further shaken by Gon, a troubled teenager who initially bullies him but later becomes an unlikely friend. Through their surprising bond and the influence of others, Yunjae embarks on a journey of emotional growth, questioning what it means to be human, to feel, and to connect.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finding Jiwon</title>
      <link>https://bestkoreanfiction.github.io/finding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bestkoreanfiction.github.io/finding/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;##Overview:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Finding Jiwon* follows Jiwon Park, a successful advertising professional in Seoul who, overwhelmed by burnout, retreats to her childhood coastal village of Haedong. What begins as a temporary escape turns into a transformative journey as she reconnects with her roots, guided by her childhood friend Hyeri, now a single mother, and Minjae, a contemplative coffee shop owner. Through the rhythms of small-town life and her efforts to revitalize the community through a festival, Jiwon rediscovers her purpose, the power of connection, and what it means to truly thrive.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Greek Lessons</title>
      <link>https://bestkoreanfiction.github.io/greek/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bestkoreanfiction.github.io/greek/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Greek Lessons&lt;/em&gt; by Han Kang is a contemplative novel about two isolated souls navigating personal grief and rediscovering connection. Set in Seoul, the story follows a young woman who has lost her voice and her Greek language teacher, who is gradually losing his sight. As their lives intertwine, their shared anguish leads to an unlikely bond, exploring the redemptive possibilities of language and human intimacy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Written in lyrical prose and translated by Deborah Smith and Emily Yae Won, the novel delves into themes of alienation, memory, and identity. A meditation on the limitations and power of language, &lt;em&gt;Greek Lessons&lt;/em&gt; invites readers to reflect on how we bridge the gaps in communication and understanding.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Human Acts</title>
      <link>https://bestkoreanfiction.github.io/human/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bestkoreanfiction.github.io/human/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Human Acts&lt;/em&gt; is a harrowing exploration of the human cost of political violence, centered on South Korea&amp;rsquo;s 1980 Gwangju Uprising. The novel opens with the tragic death of a young boy, Dong-ho, and unfolds through the perspectives of those affected by the massacre—friends, family, and survivors—spanning years of collective grief and trauma. &lt;em&gt;Human Acts&lt;/em&gt; captures the brutality of oppression and the resilience of the human spirit. Han Kang&amp;rsquo;s sparse yet powerful prose reveals the lingering effects of historical atrocities on individuals and society, making this novel a poignant meditation on the fragility of life and the enduring pursuit of justice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>If I Had Your Face</title>
      <link>https://bestkoreanfiction.github.io/cha/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bestkoreanfiction.github.io/cha/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If I Had Your Face&lt;/em&gt; plunges readers into the mesmerising and cutthroat world of contemporary Seoul. Through the lives of four women living in the same apartment building, Frances Cha weaves a tale of ambition, societal pressure, and tenuous friendships.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kyuri, an exquisitely beautiful woman, works at an exclusive room salon entertaining businessmen, but her status is threatened by a reckless mistake. Miho, her roommate, is a talented artist who returns to Korea after studying in New York, finding herself in a precarious relationship with a wealthy heir. Ara, a mute hairstylist, obsesses over a K-Pop star while supporting her best friend’s dream of extreme plastic surgery. Meanwhile, Wonna, a newlywed, grapples with the harsh realities of raising a child in a brutal economy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kim Jiyoung, Born 1982</title>
      <link>https://bestkoreanfiction.github.io/kimjy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bestkoreanfiction.github.io/kimjy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kim Jiyoung, Born 1982 tells the haunting story of a Korean everywoman who spirals into psychosis after years of enduring gender discrimination. Through Jiyoung’s life, from childhood to motherhood, Cho Nam-Joo exposes the pervasive misogyny embedded in Korean society, blending minimalist prose with real-world statistics to underscore its chilling realism.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hailed as a touchstone for feminism, the novel ignited fierce debate and became a cultural phenomenon, inspiring Korea’s modern feminist movement and resonating with readers worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our Twisted Hero</title>
      <link>https://bestkoreanfiction.github.io/hero/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bestkoreanfiction.github.io/hero/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview:&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Our Twisted Hero&lt;/em&gt; tells the story of 12-year-old Han Pyongtae, who moves from Seoul to a small-town school where he encounters Om Sokdae, the charismatic yet oppressive class monitor. As Han resists Sokdae’s rule, he becomes isolated and bullied, forcing him to confront the dynamics of power and submission. Written in 1987, this novel serves as a powerful allegory of authoritarianism, exploring themes of justice, conformity, and moral compromise through the microcosm of a classroom.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pachinko</title>
      <link>https://bestkoreanfiction.github.io/lee/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bestkoreanfiction.github.io/lee/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pachinko&lt;/em&gt; is a sweeping generational saga that spans the early 20th century to the 1980s, following the lives of a Korean immigrant family living in Japan. The story begins with Sunja, a poor but determined young woman, whose unexpected pregnancy leads her to reject her lover and accept a marriage proposal from a kind but sickly minister. Her decision to leave Korea for Japan sets off a chain of events that reverberates through her descendants.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Please Look After Mom</title>
      <link>https://bestkoreanfiction.github.io/mom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bestkoreanfiction.github.io/mom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please Look After Mom&lt;/em&gt; is an emotionally evocative novel that delves into the intricacies of family relationships and the hidden depths of a mother’s sacrifices. When sixty-nine-year-old So-nyo vanishes in the chaos of a Seoul subway station, her family’s frantic search forces them to confront their own guilt, regrets, and lack of understanding about the woman they called Mom.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Told through the alternating perspectives of her daughter, son, husband, and So-nyo herself, the novel paints a portrait of a seemingly ordinary life that reveals extraordinary layers of love, loss, and resilience. A bestseller in Korea and an international sensation, the novel is both a tribute to motherhood and a universal story of human connection.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Naked Tree</title>
      <link>https://bestkoreanfiction.github.io/tree/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bestkoreanfiction.github.io/tree/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview:&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Naked Tree&lt;/em&gt; follows Lee Kyong, a 20-year-old woman working at an Army PX in Seoul during the Korean War. Grappling with the trauma of losing her father and brothers, Lee finds herself drawn to Oak Hui-do, a quiet painter twice her age. As the war rages on, the novel explores themes of grief, survival, and the rigid norms of a Confucian society, while depicting Seoul’s fragile daily life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Old Garden</title>
      <link>https://bestkoreanfiction.github.io/garden/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bestkoreanfiction.github.io/garden/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Old Garden&lt;/em&gt; is a sweeping narrative of love, sacrifice, and resilience set against South Korea’s tumultuous political revolution of the 1980s. The story follows Hyun Woo, a political dissident imprisoned for nearly two decades, and Yoon Hee, the painter he loved and lost. Upon his release, Hyun Woo discovers Yoon Hee’s letters and diaries in the countryside home where they once sought refuge, uncovering her extraordinary life during his imprisonment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Vegetarian</title>
      <link>https://bestkoreanfiction.github.io/vegetarian/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bestkoreanfiction.github.io/vegetarian/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Vegetarian&lt;/em&gt; is an unsettling and poetic novel that delves into the depths of nonconformity, bodily autonomy, and societal repression. When Yeong-hye, an ordinary South Korean woman, decides to stop eating meat after a disturbing dream, her life spirals into chaos. Her decision disrupts her family and community, exposing deep-seated violence, patriarchal expectations, and misunderstandings about agency.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Told through three distinct perspectives—her abusive husband, her obsessive brother-in-law, and her conflicted sister—the story paints a fragmented picture of Yeong-hye’s rebellion and eventual descent. Blurring the lines between mental illness and resistance, Kang uses dark, lyrical prose to critique societal norms and gender roles. &lt;em&gt;The Vegetarian&lt;/em&gt; is a bold, provocative exploration of identity and the human spirit, hailed for its emotional intensity and allegorical depth.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The White Book</title>
      <link>https://bestkoreanfiction.github.io/white/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bestkoreanfiction.github.io/white/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The White Book&lt;/em&gt; is a reflective and poetic work about loss, grief, and memory, centered around the color white. Inspired by the death of her older sister, the book explores white objects like snow, rice, and swaddling bands, tying them to themes of purity and life’s fragility. Written in short, meditative chapters, it blurs the lines between memoir, poetry, and fiction. Critics praise its lyrical language and emotional depth, offering readers a quiet, thought-provoking experience about the connections between life, death, and remembrance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three Days in That Autumn</title>
      <link>https://bestkoreanfiction.github.io/threedays/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bestkoreanfiction.github.io/threedays/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview:&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Three Days in That Autumn&lt;/em&gt; explores the emotional turmoil of a retiring gynecologist who has devoted her career to performing abortions, a profession born from her own trauma as a rape survivor during the Korean War. Park Wan-Suh’s novella delves into themes of grief, gender oppression, and moral ambiguity, capturing the protagonist’s sardonic detachment and gradual unraveling. As her final days unfold, a deep desire to bring forth life emerges, challenging her decades of suppressed pain and isolation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who Ate Up All the Shinga?</title>
      <link>https://bestkoreanfiction.github.io/whoate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bestkoreanfiction.github.io/whoate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Who Ate Up All the Shinga?&lt;/em&gt; offers a vivid portrayal of Park Wan-suh’s early life in a small Korean village during the Japanese occupation and the Korean War. Combining acerbic wit and tender reflection, Park recounts her idyllic childhood disrupted by cultural repression, forced assimilation, and the chaos of war. The novel explores themes of identity, survival, and family dynamics, particularly through the lens of her sharp and resourceful mother. Park’s prose captures both the harsh realities of a nation in turmoil and the deeply personal struggles of a girl coming of age in a fractured world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
